International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Zimmerman, Charles S. papers, 1919-1958 [bulk 1920-1945]. 5780/014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- I. Local 22. Subject files, 1933-1958.
  - S: 1935-57. Includes CSZ comments on right-left struggle in the needle trades for Joel Seidman's book. The Needle Trades, 1941; Mrs. Morris Sigman letter thanking CSZ for his efforts in helping name a liberty ship after her late husband, Morris Sigman, February 1944. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway and Power Project: 1932-42. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Sanatoriums, Deborah Sanatorium: 1933-58. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Sanatoriums, Denver (Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society): 1934-57. Includes controversy between administrators and opposition group, 1944-49. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Sanatoriums, Jewish Chronic Disease Hospital: 1942-57. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Sanatoriums, Los Angeles Sanatorium, City of Hope: 1937-45. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Sanatoriums, Los Angeles, City of Hope: 1946-57. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Schneider, Joseph: 1933. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Seottsboro Case: 1931-39. Correspondence with Scottsboro Defense Committee. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Sick Benefits and Relief Fund, Local 22: 1927-39, 1953-58. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Simpson, Lawrence, Defense Committee: 1936. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Social Security Matters: 1934-38. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Party: 1930's. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Socialist Workers Party: 1930's. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Soderberg, John G.: 1936-37, 1942. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Spanish Dressmakers: 1933-34. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, Statements and Articles of CSZ: 1930's-50's. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Speeches, Statements and Articles of CSZ: 1930's-50's. Includes article, "Changes in the Jewish Labor Movement," Feb. 1952. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Speeches, Statements and Articles of CSZ: 1920's-50's. Newspaper clipping files. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Special Industry Committee, No. 22: 1955-56. Wage and Hour hearings for the garment industry in Puerto Rico." (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Special Industry Committee No. 22 in Puerto Rico: 1955-56. Continued (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Tailor's Progress, Controversy: 1944. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Trade Associations in Dress Industry: 1934-40's. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Trips Abroad by CSZ: 1945-46. Europe, as representative of the Jewish Labor Committee on invitation of the Norwegian Labor Federation fie labor organizations of Sweden and Denmark; includes CSZ's investigations and reports of con­ditions in Norway, Sweden, Denmark, Germany, Poland, France and England. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Trips Abroad by CSZ: 1945-46. Europe, continued (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Trips Abroad by CSZ: 1948. Israel. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Trips Abroad by CSZ: 1934. Puerto Rico. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Trips Abroad by CSZ: 1958. Geneva, Switzerland, as delegate to the Textile Industrial Commission of the Int'l. Labor Organization. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Trotsky, Leon, and Trotskyites: 1930's-47. Letters, statements from American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, 1936-37; releases and copies of letters petitioning the Nuremberg tribunal to examine charge made at Moscow trials that Trotsky conspired for war with Nazi Germany, 1946-47. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - U:1933-55. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Unemployment: 1931-34. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Includes form letters from Emergency Conference on Unemployment, 1931-32; Joint Committee on Unemployment, 1934; United Action Conference on Work, Relief and Unemployment, 1934. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Unemployment, Garment Industry: 1930's-40's. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Union for Democratic Action: 1941-46. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Union Health Center, Los Angeles: 1953, 1955. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Union Health Center, NYC: 1933-58. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Union Labor Life Insurance; 1936-57. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Unions, General, A-O: 1934-53. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Unions, General, P-Z: 1933-37. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Workers Union, National: 1946-58. Correspondence with H.L.Mitchell; includes Nat'l. Farm Labor Union. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Automobile Workers of America, United: 1936-54. Includes letters from group called "Unity," 1938. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Bags and Baggage, International Brother­hood of Red Caps: 1937-39. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Building Service Employees International Union: 1934-37. Correspondence and Local 22 releases re 1934 elevator strike of Local 32-B. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Clothing Workers of America, Amalgamated: 1934-52. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Doll and Toy Workers Union, International (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Union of: 1949, 1956-57. Includes correspondence re jurisdictional disputes between Doll and Toy Workers Union and Local 132 of ILGWU. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Electrical Workers, International Brotherhood: 1935-37. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Fur Workers Union: 1935-56. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Hosiery Workers, American Federation: 1937-55. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Hospital Employees' Union: 1936. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union: 1934-56. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Ladies' Apparel Shipping Clerks Union, Local 19953: 1935-36. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Longshoremen's Association, International: 1953-57. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Guild of New York, and American Newspaper Guild: 1935-47. (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Office Employees International Union: 1936-55. Includes correspondence re negotiations, agreements with Local 22. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Pocketbook Workers Union: 1937-43. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Retail Unions: 1936-56. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Rubber Workers Union: 1936-58. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Seafarers International Union: 1936-58. Also includes Norman Thomas statement on internal conflict in National Maritime Union, 1950. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Sleeping Car Porters, Brotherhood of: 1937-58. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - State, County and Municipal Workers of America: 1936-55. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Steel Workers Organizing Committee; 1936-37. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Teachers Union: 1934-58. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America, International Brotherhood of: 1938-56. (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Technical, Editorial and Office Assistants Union: 1935. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Textile Workers Union of America: 1934-54. Includes agreement between Textile Workers Union and ILGWU, 1934; Textile Workers Organizing Committee reports and incoming letters on devel­oping situations in organizing, 1937-38. (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Theatrical Unions: 1935-37, 1947. (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Transport Workers Union: 1935-38. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Trucking Industry: 1949-56. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Yiddish Actors and Yiddish Writers Union: 1936-45. (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Cloakmakers United Front Committee United Front Committee of Cloakmakers United Cloak and Dressmakers Progressive League Unity Committee, Cloak, Dress and Furrier Unions Printed material, 1930's. (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - United Hebrew Trades: 1934-50. (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - United Jewish Appeal: 1940-53. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - United States Government, Congress and Departments: 1934-58, 1964. Includes Department. of Labor, President's Com­mittee on Equal Employment Opportunity, May 1964. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Government, N.Y. City and State: 1934-58. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - V: 1935-54. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Veterans: 1946-56. Includes Jewish War Veterans, Veterans League of America. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Vrataric, Frank: 1936. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - W: 1933-57. Includes CSZ letter to J.H. Waldman on Communism and Communists in America, 1941. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - WEVD: 1934-40. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Welfare Council of New York: 1939-45. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Wiesen, Max, and Sons, Co.: 1943, 1952-56. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Women's Matters: 1936-43. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Women's Trade Union League: 1933-42. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Women's Trade Union League: 1943-55. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Workers' Defense League: 1937-58. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Workmen's Circle: 1933-41. Includes Dressmakers Branch 122. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Workmen's Circle: 1942-58. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Works Progress Administration: 1934-39. Correspondence re unemployment, appropriation of fund relief, labor activities. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - WPA, Sewing Project: 1935-39. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - WPA, Teachers Union: 1936-39. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - WPA, Workers Alliance of America: 1935-39. Includes letters from Workers Unemployed Union of N.Y., 1935. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - World War II: 1930's-49. Form letters, circulars from committees against war; post-1938: material on war effort and aid to Allies, letters to Cordell Hull, Local 22 resolutions, report and recommendations on effect of war on New York's women's garment industry, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - World War II, American League Against War and Fascism: 1933-36. Correspondence, releases, printed material. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - World War II, American League Against War and Fascism: 1933-34. Minutes and reports. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - World War II, Committee for Amnesty for All Objectors to War and Conscription: 1946-47. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - World War II, Government Agencies: 1942-45. Includes Israel Feinberg recommendations to War Work Emergency Committee of GEB on garment industry, Feb. 1942. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Peoples Committee for United Action Against Fascism and Anti-Semitism: 1937-45. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - World War II, Keep America Out of War Committee: 1938-40. Includes CSZ letter of resignation, 1940. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - World War II, Members in Armed Forces: 1943-45. Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - World War II, Refugees: 1935-47. Includes Emergency Rescue Committee, Inc., ltrs, from Francis A. Henson of the Emergency Committee in Aid of Political Refugees from Nazism. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - World War II, United Service Organi­zation (USO): 1942-46. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - World Youth Congress: 1938. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - World's Fair: 1939. Union's purchasing N.Y. Fair Bonds. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Y: 1938-57. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - YIVO Institute for Jewish Research: 1939-45, 1950-52. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - YIVO Institute for Jewish Research; 1953-58. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Z: 1942-58. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Zimmerman, Israel: 1946. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Photographs. (Box 39, Folder 5-11)
- II. Subject files, 1919-1932., Documents dealing mainly with left-wing and right-wing struggle in the needle trades. Substantial material on the garment industry and its affiliates. Communist and anti-communist activities in the USA. (1919-32)
  Scope and Contents
  Types of items include: correspondence, reports, minutes, broadside collection, newspaper clippings.
  - American Civil Liberties Union: 1927, Controversy over position of the ACLU concerning the Committee for the Defense of Needle Trades Workers. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Anarchist Workers' Group (Cloak and Dressmakers Union): 1920's. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Breslow, Israel; Brown, Bishop William, of Montgomery, Ala.: 1928, 1931. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Cases: 1921, 1925, 1927, 1932. Includes charges against CSZ in the above years (except 1927); Supreme Court, N.Y. County, Luigi Antonini vs Louis Hyman, et al.: Salvatore Ninfo vs Louis Hyman, et al., and the Association of Dress Manufacturers, Inc., vs Louis Hyman, et al., 1927. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Clothing Workers Union, Amalgamated: 1920's-30's. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Committees, Committee of 15, 25, 50 and 100: 1920's-30's. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Communist Party U.S.A. (Workers /communist/Party): 1925-29. Correspondence; includes Herbert Benjamin letter (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - 1928; William Z. Foster letter, 1928; letters from Benjamin Gitlow, Charles E. Ruthenberg and William W. Weinstone. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Communist Party U.S.A.: 1918-30 's. Printed material dealing mainly with all facets of trade unionism especially the garment industry; includes constitutions of the Communist Party of America, 1920; minutes of district meetings, reports of committees, statements. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Communist Party U.S.A.: 1918-30's. Printed material, cont'd; includes reports of Earl Browder on American trade union movement. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Communist Party U.S.A.: 1918-30's. Printed material, continued. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Communist Party U.S.A.: 1920's-30's. Publications, includes the Red Needle. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Communist Party U.S.A. (Central Execu­tive Committee), Industrial Depart­ment: 1920's. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Section Meetings: 1921. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group), Lovestone Group: 1929-39, Letters, bulletins, reports, statements, material from Revolutionary Age. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group), Lovestone Group: 1929-39. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group),Lovestone Group: 1929-39. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group), Lovestone Group: 1929-39. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group), Lovestone Group: 1929-39. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Communist Party U.S.A., Majority Group (post-1933 known as the Opposition Group), Lovestone Group: 1929-39. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Communist Party, Opposition Group: 1933-39. Letters, form letters, reports. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Communist Party, Opposition Group: 1933-39. Printed material. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Communist Party, Opposition Group: 1933-39. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Communist Party, Opposition Group: 1933-39. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Communist Party, Opposition Group: 1933-39. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Conference for Progressive Labor Action: c. 1931. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Dress Manufacturers Association and Ladies Waist and Dressmakers Union (Local 22): 1919-20. Minutes of conferences affecting the welfare of dress industry. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Dressmakers Progressive League and Dressmakers Trade Union Circle, and Dressmakers United Front Committee: 1930's. Programs, printed material. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Dressmakers Welfare Club: 1920's. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. Printed material from various fractions of Furriers. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Fur and Leather Workers Union, Int'l.: 1920's-57. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - internal Strife, ILGWU: 1926-28, 1931. Includes newspaper clippings. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - International Council of Trade and Industrial Unions, American Bureau: 1920's. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Joint Action Committee, Locals 2, 9, 22: 1920's. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Joint Action Committee, Locals 2, 9, 22: 1920's. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Left Groups of the Cloakmakers' Locals: 1920's-30's. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Local 1, N.Y.C.: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Local 9, N.Y.C.: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Local 10, N.Y.C.: 1920's-50's. Includes The Cutter. 1926-35. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Local 10, N.Y.C.: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Local 10, N.Y.C.: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Local 35, N.Y.C.: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Local 50, Philadelphia, Pa.: 1920's. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Local 72, N.Y.C.: 1920's. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Local 100, Chicago, Ill.: 1919-20's. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Losovsky, A. (Alec Levine): 1920's. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Lovestone, Jay: 1927-40. Correspondence between Zimmerman and Lovestone; letters and reports from individuals to Lovestone on all facets of trade union activities; includes letters and reports from Paul Berg, Al Sands, Elmer Hamm, Joe Engelstein, Glenn Shadduck and Jack Hering. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Millinery Workers Union: 1920's-30's. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Documents. From right and left wings, many not identified or dated, almost all dealing with garment industry. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - National Workers Committee for Organizing Jewish Workers in Israel: 1920's. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1920's-30's. Letters, reports, statements and substantial printed material re all facets of Union activities. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1920's-30's. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1920's-30's. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1920's-30's. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1920's-30's. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1928-31. Dressmakers Bulletin. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1928-34. The Needle Worker. Boston Needle Worker. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Needle Trades Workers Unity League: 1920's-30's. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - New Workers School: 1932. Syllabus for fall term. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - New York Cloakmakers Union Strike: 1926. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - New York Dressmakers Union Strikes: 1929, 1932. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - President's Office, ILGWU: 1923-27. Includes letters, form letters, GEB statements re internal strife. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Red International of Labor Unions (R.I.L.U.) and Needle Workers International Propaganda and Action Committee (IPAC): 1920's. Reports and resolutions. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Shop Delegate Propaganda Committee: 1920's. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Silk and Dye Workers Union: 1930's-Strike in Paterson, N.J. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Trade Union Educational League: 1922-24, 1927. Correspondence and letters from William Z. Foster, J.W. Johnstone, Jack Jampolsky. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Trade Union Educational League: 1920's. Minutes, printed material, reports of activities in needle trades. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Trade Union Educational League: 1920's. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Trade Union Educational League: 1920's. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Workers Council of the Cloak and Suit Industry and Workers Council of the White Goods Industry: 1919. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Workers Council of the Waist and Dress Industry: 1919. (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Yar Yachno: 1930's-40. Letters, leaflets. Personal Documents, Publications, and Newspaper Clippings. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Personal Documents. Includes letters from Samuel Lipman during his stay in prison, 1919-20; letters from individuals in Soviet Union. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Personal Documents, prior to 1933. Printed items. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Personal Documents, prior to 1933. Printed items. (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Publications. Union Worker (issued by the Union Workers Group), March 1926-Feb. 1927; The Free Word (issued by the Unemployed Committee of the Cloak and Dressmakers Union), Dec. 1941-Aug. 1942 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Publications. Monthly Jewish Bulletin (issued by Majority Group of the Communist Party), Dec, 1929-June 1930; The Workers Struggle (issued by the Communist Party USA), Dec. 1929-June 1930. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Publications. Union Vanguard, Jan. 1938-Mar. 1942; The Cloak Finisher (issued by Local 9 opposition). Jan-March 1942; Yiddisher Kemfer (organ of the Poale-zion-Zeire Zion of America), Jan. 1939. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Publications. The Voice of Unity (issued by the National Organization Committee of the ILGWU),. 1928. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Publications: 1920's-30's. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Publications: 1920's-30's. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Original Broadsides. (Box 47)
  - Original Broadsides. (Box 48)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1925. Files dealing with garment industry. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files; 1926. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1927. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1928-30. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1931-32. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1933. (Box 49, Folder 6-7)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1934. (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1935. (Box 49, Folder 10-11)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1936. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1937. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1938. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1939. (Box 50, Folder 4-5)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1940. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1941. (Box 50, Folder 7-9)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files: 1945. Trips abroad. (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings Files. (Box 50, Folder 11)